<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[research - Guangyuan Piao ]]></title><description><![CDATA[CS Lecturer/Assistant Professor at Maynooth University. Interested in understanding user and machine behaviors via AI, ML, DL]]></description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><image><url>http://localhost:2368/favicon.png</url><title>research - Guangyuan Piao </title><link>http://localhost:2368/</link></image><generator>Ghost 3.2</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 21:58:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/tag/research/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Topic: Anomaly Detection]]></title><description><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p><strong>Anomaly Detection</strong> is a data analysis task which detects anomalies from a given dataset is important in many contexts and domains such as medical and health, fraud detection in finance, and computer systems &amp; networks <sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn1" id="fnref1">[1]</a></sup>. The same problem has also been terms as:</p>
<ul>
<li>outlier detection</li>
<li>novelty detection</li>
<li>deviation detection</li></ul>]]></description><link>http://localhost:2368/about/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5e09207482f7780f240f272e</guid><category><![CDATA[topic]]></category><category><![CDATA[research]]></category><category><![CDATA[post]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Guangyuan Piao]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 23:01:24 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p><strong>Anomaly Detection</strong> is a data analysis task which detects anomalies from a given dataset is important in many contexts and domains such as medical and health, fraud detection in finance, and computer systems &amp; networks <sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn1" id="fnref1">[1]</a></sup>. The same problem has also been terms as:</p>
<ul>
<li>outlier detection</li>
<li>novelty detection</li>
<li>deviation detection</li>
<li>exception mining</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="definitionofanomaly">Definition of Anomaly</h2>
<p><em>Anomalies</em> denote patterns that do not conform expected behavior, and hav e been refered to as other terms such as <em>outliers</em>, <em>discordant observations</em>, <em>exceptions</em>, <em>aberrations</em>, <em>surprises</em>, <em>peculiarities</em> or <em>contaminants</em> in different application domains <sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn2" id="fnref2">[2]</a></sup>. Among many definitions in the literature, one of the widely accepted definition of anomaly by Hawkins <sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn3" id="fnref3">[3]</a></sup> is defined as follows.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>An anomaly is an observation which deviates so much from other observations as to arouse suspicions that it was generated by a different mechanism.</p>
</blockquote>
<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<!-- parklize_main_Blog1_728x90_as -->
<p><ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:inline-block;width:728px;height:90px" data-ad-client="ca-pub-9673038949803914" data-ad-slot="4115851559"></ins></p>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>
<h2 id="relationshipstonoisenovelty">Relationships to <em>noise</em> &amp; <em>novelty</em></h2>
<p>The key distinction between a <em>noise</em> and <em>anomaly</em> is the interestingness of the pattern to the analyst. Noise is not of interest to the analyst while anomaly is.</p>
<p>The distinction between novel patterns and anomaly ones is that the novel patterns are typically incorporated into the normal model after being detected <sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn2" id="fnref2:1">[2:1]</a></sup>.</p>
<h2 id="typesofanomalies">Types of Anomalies</h2>
<p>Usually, anomalies can be categorized into three main types <sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn1" id="fnref1:1">[1:1]</a></sup><sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn4" id="fnref4">[4]</a></sup>:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Point Anomalies</strong>: A point anomaly is any point which deviates from the range of expected values in a given dataset. For example, a memory usage value which has 3 standard deviation from the mean can be considered as a point anomaly. The majority of previous studies has been focused on point anomalies.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Collective Anomalies</strong>: A homogeneous group/set of data points deviating from the normal <em>regions</em> of the rest of the data. For example, an unexpected streak of low throughput values may be considered as collective anomalies when compared with higher ones in the past observation window.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Contextual Anomalies</strong>: Anomalies that manifest only under certain environments/contexts. For example, high expenditure during a festive period can be considered as normal in the context, e.g., black friday. Contextual anomalies require that the data has a set of <em>contextual attributes</em> (to define a context), and a set of <em>behavior attributes</em> (to detect anomalies within a context).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Pattern Anomalies</strong>: The shapes of some performance metrics when plotted are know to exhibit specific pattern, and the violation of this can be considered as pattern anomalies. This can be seen as a special case of collective anomalies.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<script async src="//pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<!-- parklize_main_Blog1_728x90_as -->
<p><ins class="adsbygoogle" style="display:inline-block;width:728px;height:90px" data-ad-client="ca-pub-9673038949803914" data-ad-slot="4115851559"></ins></p>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({
          google_ad_client: "ca-pub-9673038949803914",
          enable_page_level_ads: true
     });
</script>
<h2 id="inputoutput">Input &amp; Output</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Input</strong>: a set of data instances where each data instance can be described using a set of attributes. Each data instance can be <em>univariate</em> (one attribute) or <em>multivariate</em> (multiple attributes).</li>
<li><strong>Output</strong>: labels and/or scores. Scoring mechanisom allows analyst to use a domain specific threshold to filter relevant anomalies.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="typesofsolutionswithrespecttolabelconditions">Types of Solutions with respect to Label Conditions</h2>
<p>Based on the availability of the labels associated with data instances, anomaly detection techniques can be categorized into three types <sup class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn2" id="fnref2:2">[2:2]</a></sup>:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Supervised Anomaly Detection</strong>: It assumes labeled training set is available, which is not always the case. In addition, even it is availble, the numbers of anomaly and non-anomaly labels are imbalanced.</li>
<li><strong>Semisupervised Anomaly Detection</strong>: It assumes that we have a training set with the normal class. A typical approach in this stream is to build a model for the normal class, and use it to identify anomalies in the test data.</li>
<li><strong>Unsupervised Anomaly Detection</strong>: No need for training data, and thus is widely applicable. It assumes that normal instances are far more frequent than anomalies in the test data.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="references">References</h2>
<hr class="footnotes-sep">
<section class="footnotes">
<ol class="footnotes-list">
<li id="fn1" class="footnote-item"><p>Ahmed, Mohiuddin, Abdun Naser Mahmood, and Jiankun Hu. &quot;A survey of network anomaly detection techniques.&quot; Journal of Network and Computer Applications 60 (2016): 19-31. <a href="#fnref1" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a> <a href="#fnref1:1" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn2" class="footnote-item"><p>Chandola, Varun, Arindam Banerjee, and Vipin Kumar. &quot;Anomaly detection: A survey.&quot; ACM computing surveys (CSUR) 41.3 (2009): 15. <a href="#fnref2" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a> <a href="#fnref2:1" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a> <a href="#fnref2:2" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn3" class="footnote-item"><p>Hawkins, Douglas M. Identification of outliers. Vol. 11. London: Chapman and Hall, 1980. <a href="#fnref3" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn4" class="footnote-item"><p>Ibidunmoye, Olumuyiwa, Francisco Hernández-Rodriguez, and Erik Elmroth. &quot;Performance anomaly detection and bottleneck identification.&quot; ACM Computing Surveys (CSUR) 48.1 (2015): 4. <a href="#fnref4" class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown-->]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>